<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>indiroot</title>
    <link>http://indiroot.ca/</link>
    <description>Recent content on indiroot</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 18:51:23 +0430</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://indiroot.ca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aboriginal Creation Stories</title>
      <link>http://indiroot.ca/post/aboriginal-creation-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 18:51:23 +0430</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://indiroot.ca/post/aboriginal-creation-stories/</guid>
      <description>Creation stories describe the origins of the cosmos and the interrelations of its elements. Among these tales is what scholars often refer to as the &amp;ldquo;Earth Diver myth&amp;rdquo;. This is a story where a Great Spirit or cultural hero dives, or orders animals to dive, into the primeval water to bring back mud, out of which the Earth is fashioned. In some versions of the story, Earth is formed on the back of a turtle; Turtle Island is a popular name used by certain Indigenous peoples for the land of North America.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indigenous Religious Institutions</title>
      <link>http://indiroot.ca/post/indigenous-religious-institutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://indiroot.ca/post/indigenous-religious-institutions/</guid>
      <description>Different Indigenous nations have their own religious institutions and sacred practices. Many Plains Indigenous peoples participate in the Sun Dance, while Coast Salish peoples typically engage in sacred winter ceremonies. The Haudenosaunee celebrate the Green Corn Ceremony, and some follow the False Face Society. Among the Ojibwe, the Midewiwin is a spiritual society and essential part of the Anishinaabe worldview. Medicine bundles, objects of ritual that are specific to the person carrying them, are common among the spiritual traditions of various Indigenous peoples, including the Siksika, Cree, and Ojibwe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religion and Spirituality</title>
      <link>http://indiroot.ca/post/religion-and-spirituality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://indiroot.ca/post/religion-and-spirituality/</guid>
      <description>First Nation, Métis, and Inuit religions in Canada vary widely and consist of complex social and cultural customs for addressing the sacred and the supernatural. The influence of Christianity through settlers, missionaries, and government policy significantly altered life for Indigenous peoples. In some communities, this resulted in hybridized religious practices; while in others, European religion replaced traditional spiritual practices entirely. Though historically suppressed by colonial administrators and missionaries, especially from the late 19th- to mid-20th centuries, many contemporary Indigenous communities have revived, or continue to practice, traditional spirituality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regional and Cultural Diversity of Indigenous Peoples</title>
      <link>http://indiroot.ca/post/regional-and-cultural-diversity-of-indigenous-peoples/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://indiroot.ca/post/regional-and-cultural-diversity-of-indigenous-peoples/</guid>
      <description>Indigenous peoples, both historical and contemporary, in North America can be divided into 10 cultural areas. Only the first six areas are found within the borders of Canada:
 Arctic Subarctic Northwest Coast Plateau Plains Eastern Woodlands (sometimes referred to as the Northeast) Southeast Southwest Great Basin California  Contemporary political borders in North America do not reflect (and often overlap) traditional lands. For example, the Mohawk Nation at Akwesasne straddles both provincial (Québec and Ontario) and international (New York State) borders, as its existence predates the establishment of the international border in 1783.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indigenous People of Canada</title>
      <link>http://indiroot.ca/post/indigenous-peoples-in-canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://indiroot.ca/post/indigenous-peoples-in-canada/</guid>
      <description>In this very brief article, a few definitions and demographic data on the indigenous people residing in Canada is presented.
Introduction In Canada, the term Indigenous people (or Aboriginal people) refers to First Nations (Indians), Métis, and Inuit people. These are the original inhabitants of the land that is now Canada. The Inuit primarily inhabit the northern regions of Canada. Their homeland, known as Inuit Nunangat, includes much of the land, water, and ice contained in the Arctic region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>http://indiroot.ca/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://indiroot.ca/about/</guid>
      <description>At indiroot, we are aiming to provide a platform for indigenous people to promote their culture by utilizing Augmented Reality (AR) while selling their handcraft and art.
Achievements  Accepted into Manitoba Accelerator SUV Program on Jun. 4th. Invited to pitch at TiE Vancouver Demo Day on Feb. 11th as one of the 20 top teams.  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
